"Previously on The Mentalist..."
Jane has worked out that
Red John is one of seven men.
"But Red John also knows
the seven names on Jane's list."
I'm gonna give you the seven names
and I need you to put a G.P.S. bug
on each of their cell phones.
- The wires are up.
- Okay.
We watch them like hawks.
We log everywhere they go 24/7.
"We have an anonymous tip
directed to your unit."
"A person or persons in distress
at 5570 west Huron."
Brett Partridge is there.
Oh God! Partridge.
Tiger...
Tiger.
Just that hammer...
you see that up there?
Is that blood
on the hitting side?
Could be.
I'll call forensics.
Did you see that?
He did not want to go up that ladder.
Didn't the psychiatrist's office say
that Red John was afraid of heights?
Where did you come from?
Give me your hand.
While investigating Red John
homeland security's begun
to suspect the existence
of a powerful secret organization
within California law enforcement.
We're looking for partners within the F.B.I.
lower level guys
- that we're sure we can trust.
- That's me.
We should talk some more.
Get in the car.
- Do I have a choice?
- No.
I was wrong about you.
You're not Red John.
You're hunting him,
same as me.
We both want our revenge
and only one of us is going to get it.
- Please tell me who the suspects are.
- No.
You understand I'm gonna
have to torture you.
Put your hands in the air!
Jane, you all right?
- Are you gonna finish this thing?
- Yes.
There is a powerful organization
within law enforcement.
It's a lot bigger
than you thought.
It's not just the big boys, either.
They even let lower level guys
like me in.
Agent Kirkland tried to escape.
You had no choice
but to use deadly force.
Do you understand?
Tiger tiger.
Hold the elevator.
So, dad, can we ride
on the cable car?
Yeah, you bet.
- Then lunch in Chinatown?
- Again?
I like those noodles,
and the dumplings.
Come on, come on, come on...
Whoa! What the heck?!
Hey, how do you think you are?
You can't shove my kid.
Don't run away from me!
Hey! Hey!
You open this door!
I'm complaining to the management!
You hear me?
- You all right, Buddy? He get ya? Huh?
- I'm okay.
Mr. Parkman?
Sir, this is hotel security.
Mr. Parkman, I'm gonna have to ask you
to open the door, please.
Mr. Parkman? Sir?
I'm coming in.
Help.
- He stabbed me.
- Who stabbed you?
Mr. Parkman?
Oh, Jeez. Mr. Parkman?
Get some help.
Call 9-1-1. Room 8-1-5.
Deceased white male.
And you say the victim
appeared worried?
Yeah, he was looking over
his shoulder
when he got in the elevator,
like he was being chased.
- Yeah. He had something in a paper bag.
- Yeah.
- And what sort of time was this?
- 10:55.
I entered the room at 10:58 P.M.
the victim, Chad Parkman
was on the floor
in some distress.
He stated he had been stabbed
by another individual.
Although he appeared to be
alone in the room.
Lisbon. This is the head of hotel security.
A fount of information.
Agent Lisbon from the CBI.
- She'll be happy to listen to you.
- Do we have a murder weapon?
No, ma'am, nor have I been
able to establish
any means of egress
used by the killer.
Uh, what about a paper bag?
The kid outside mentioned a paper bag.
Just scraps on the toilet.
Must have been shredded and flushed.
- Any idea what was in it?
- No idea.
Maybe the perp who Killed him
took it.
Hey, boss.
Just got a call on the radio.
Another homicide nearby.
Attempted carjacking, looks like.
- Related?
- Probably not. Thought I'd check it out.
All right. Come back
as quick as you can.
Okay.
When I was outside the room,
I heard them struggling
then heard the victim cry out
when he was stabbed.
But then I got the door open...
- he was all alone.
- Window's open.
It's a long way down,
and a long way up to the roof.
I don't think he went that way.
- So, what? Magic?
- Nope.
Just a trick.
And we all know how good
you are at those, don't we?
Tricks, I mean.
- Hey, Teresa.
- Ray.
What are you doing here?
You don't work at the CBI anymore.
- I'm with a client.
- He works for Visualize.
He does, and this is
a Visualize matter.
- Who are they?
- This is Jason Cooper.
Errand boy for cult leader
Bret Stiles
And Ray Haffner,
who is a member of the cult.
Visualize is not a cult
and it is exactly bigotry like that
- that leads to murders like this.
- What are you talking about?
Chad Parkman was a prominent member
of the Visualize community.
We view his murder
as a hate crime.
Mr. Haffner is to be included
in your investigation.
Purely as a victim's advocate
but I do like the idea of working
with you again, Teresa.
I appreciate your concern,
Mr. Cooper
but we never let civilians
in our investigations... ever.
- Never ever?
- Well, he's...
- he's different.
- I'm different.
I have a letter here signed
by the lieutenant governor
Inviting Mr. Haffner
to join the investigation.
To observe. That's all.
Read the letter, agent Lisbon.
I am confident you'll want to grant
the lieutenant governor's request.
So... any ideas
on the case yet?
- Just questions.
- It's a stumper, isn't it?
Speaking of which, how's your
Red John investigation going?
In the bag.
You know, we study you
in Visualize now.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Your blind struggle
against fate.
So heroic. So fruitless.
Bret says there's a lot to be learned
from watching Patrick Jane, so... we all do.
So much anger.
- It's not good for you.
- Anger? I'm not angry.
Annihilating rage.
About what, I have no idea.
You don't know anything about me.
Just what's written on your face.
You're so much smarter
than everybody else, right?
But it isn't helping you
catch Red John, is it?
Here's a switch for you.
I'm gonna predict your future.
There's a comeuppance
headed your way.
You're a worse psychic
than you were a cop.
Hey.
So our victim...
Chad Parkman...
Was a successful Olympic
gymnastics coach.
- He had a facility out in Marin.
- What was he doing at the hotel?
Sports health conference.
He was the keynote speaker.
What about the Visualize angle?
Did you find anything there?
Nothing I.D.ing him
as a member.
- You think Cooper's lying?
- I don't know.
If Bret stiles sends
his second-in-command
and private security, it's important
to Visualize somehow.
Let's play nice.
I'll go make up with Cooper.
I want you to go through
the security tapes with Haffner.
He likes you. Just be helpful
and accommodating. Get him talking.
Pump him for every bit of information
that you can.
- Sure, boss. I know what to do.
- But be careful.
- You know.
- Yeah.
Hey. You wanna come with me
to talk to Cooper?
Nope.
We don't want to spook him.
I'll take Cho to Parkman's gym.
He can talk reps and curls
and I'll take a little look around.
All right. I'll call you
if I find anything out.
"That's right. Point your toes, perfect."
Nice... Nice...
All right, now...
Stick the landing, Kimmy.
Good...
That's right!
Wow. She's impressive.
You know, Rio 2016...
that's the goal.
And, Parkman was
your first choice as coach?
You bet. Parkman
offering to coach your kid?
Ah, you know, he's probably
too busy with Kimmy
to take your kid on,
but, uh, he's the best.
- Yeah?
- Oh, yeah.
He got Kimmy to bear down
in ways I never could.
She's always texting
with friends
wanting to go for pizzas
on a Friday night with boys.
You know? No more of that.
- Thank goodness.
- Yeah. Yeah.
And I never felt I have to worry
about her being alone with him.
Well, that would be important,
wouldn't it?
- Yeah. All right, let's go.
- Thanks.
Did Mr. Parkman ever talk
about his personal life?
No, never. I would ask questions sometimes
just to be polite, you know
and he would just be very vague.
Thank you.
- Excuse me...
- Whoa, careful.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Guess I shouldn't have
worn heels.
My little sister's
interested in gymnastics.
Could you help explain
this pricing to me?
- I don't work here.
- Oh. I...
Excuse me.
You're the guy from CBI?
- That's right. Agent Kimball Cho.
- I'm Bill Mylar, co-owner.
- We talked on the phone.
- Right.
Oh, wait. You're here
investigating something?
A murder.
I thought you were gonna come
directly to my office.
We decided to talk to some of your
clientele. You don't mind, do you?
Anything that helps, but the truth is
everybody here at the gym loved Chad.
People always say that
about the dead.
Seldom is it true. Is there someplace
private we can talk?
So... You're a policeman. Duh!
I'm so sorry.
I'm embarrassed.
- Somebody died?
- Yes.
Oh, my gosh, a murder?
- Did you know Chad Parkman?
- The gym owner?
No. What happened?
There's a staff member right over there.
They can tell you about the pricing.
Tough guy, huh?
Thanks.
Excuse me. Could you help me
with this pricing?
I'm sorry we got off
on the wrong foot.
Now I want you to know that
I am completely committed
to finding whoever
killed Mr. Parkman.
Our interests are the same.
In light of that, I was wondering
if you could give me
a little history as to
Mr. Parkman's role in Visualize.
I haven't been able to find any evidence
linking him to the organization.
Chad's eyes were opened
to the truth only recently.
But he was deeply committed.
- We had big plans for him.
- What kind of plans?
Chad Parkman had very positive
name recognition across all quadrants.
The most commonly used word
to describe him was "trustworthy."
So you were gonna use him
for public outreach?
Something like that, yes.
Do you think that's why
someone killed him?
It's a strong possibility.
What was Mr. Parkman's
relationship with Bret Stiles?
Bret Stiles was a guide
and a beacon for Chad
- as he is for all of us.
- And where is Mr. Stiles?
- I can't be certain.
- Really? You have no idea where he is?
It is not necessary for me
to know where he is in physical space.
If he needs me,
he will find me.
Would you excuse me?
Hey, Rigs.
I'm at the carjacking scene.
So the victim here
got shot.
On the seat next to him,
we have a bloody knife.
"Do you think it's the same knife
that was used to kill Parkman?"
Yeah, it could be.
You can see the hotel from here.
- Get that knife to the lab.
- Will do, boss.
- "I'm on my way to C.B.I."
- Okay.
Parkman was the face of the business.
I do the business.
- And how is business?
- Phenomenal.
We're planning on expanding
to the southeast, northeast, every place.
Now I don't know
what we're gonna do.
Well, there are upsides to Parkman's death
let's be honest.
What are you talking about?
You know, that's a very sick thing to say.
Well, think about all the sympathetic
press coverage.
That's free publicity
right there.
Plus the whole Visualize mess
goes away.
What are you talking about?
Well, you've heard
of Visualize, right?
Of course I have. It's that wacko cult.
What does that have to do with anything?
Yeah, well, Parkman was
a member of Visualize.
- You didn't know that?
- No.
- You sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Hey.
Tell me, did Chad talk about
Visualize a lot?
Yeah, sure.
He was a member.
Some kind of weird
self-help group.
It's not my thing, but if it helped him coach
all the power to him.
And, Mr. Mylar...
How did he feel about Visualize?
Mylar hated that stuff.
You'd see them arguing about it all the time.
Oh, really?
Hated it, did he?
You got me.
A foolish lie.
The truth...I was mad as hell
about Visualize.
I'm trying to expand our business
he Joins some Moonbat cult?
We fought about it a lot, so now
I feel guilty that we ended on bad terms.
- But I didn't kill him.
- You didn't, did you?
Boss wants us back.
Lisbon, you find something?
The knife that Killed Parkman
at the site of Rigsby's Carjacking.
- What was the Carjacking victim's name?
- Frost. Devin Frost.
Tell me about Devin Frost.
Devin? He used to work here.
He's a good kid.
Interesting news.
The plot thickens.
Plot thickens.
Lisbon?
She's gone.
We're in an alley
about a block from the hotel.
We found a gun.
Is this the gun
used to kill Frost?
Yeah, looks like it.
And there's duct tape on the barrel.
"From the silencer."
Well, get it to ballistics.
Make sure it's a match.
See if we can get
any fingerprints.
Will do. Bye.
- Looks like we've got the gun.
- Yeah?
It's on its way to forensics now,
but it's a pretty sure bet.
Well, as soon as Haffner gets here,
we'll get started.
I don't like it, boss.
Haffner shouldn't
even be in our offices.
He's one of Jane's
Red John suspects.
And he's a member
of Visualize.
Which is run by another
Red John suspect.
We should be investigating him.
Not letting him join our investigation.
We don't really have a choice.
Might as well make the most of it. Haffner!
Teresa.
Lovely as always.
- Guys. So what have we got so far?
- Well, let's see.
Parkman entered the hotel at 10:48.
He was anxious, and witnesses got
the impression that he was being pursued.
He has an altercation in the elevator
and Parkman flees to his room
at approximately 10:51.
And at 10:58, hotel security
opened Parkman's room
to find him dying on the floor
with a stab wound.
At 12 past 11:00,
police and E.M.T.s arrive
but they pronounce Parkman
dead at the scene.
Nobody could have entered
or left the room
during that time period
without being seen.
Here's the park.
The hotel's on the one side
and this is where Devin Frost
was murdered...
On the other side of the park.
Now, in front's car, there's a knife
with Parkman's blood on the blade
and Frost's fingerprints
on the handle.
We also found
a homemade silencer in the car.
And we found the gun that belongs
to the silencer here in the alley
which, given the timeline,
seems to be a physical impossibility.
So... Frost stabbed Parkman
and somehow left the hotel
without being seen
and then an unknown assailant
killed Frost?
It would look that way.
The silencer didn't work too well.
We have three witnesses
who heard a gunshot around 10:57.
So Frost got shot
in his car at almost the exact same time
that he was supposedly
in the hotel stabbing Parkman?
- Which is impossible.
- Correct.
So, you're looking
for an unknown suspect
who is a magician or quite possibly
a wizard of some kind.
Great work, guys.
We've brought in Mylar,
the owner of the gym.
We're hoping he can shed
some light on this
or at least give us
a plausible motive.
Okay then. Well, I'm so glad we got
the "A" team working this case.
I'm gonna go back to the hotel
and look things over again.
Ciao, kids.
Jane said not to Lean on Mylar too hard.
Just ask him about
Parkman and Frost
- and see how he reacts.
- You got it.
Hey, sorry to interrupt.
Weird report just
came over my desk.
It's about Bob Kirkland.
What, the psychotic homeland
security agent we arrested?
Yeah. He's dead.
Dead? How'd he die?
The report says he was Killed
attempting to escape from prison.
Seriously?
- Doesn't sound right, does it?
- No, it doesn't.
I should check it out, right?
- Find out what happened and why.
- Will do, boss.
- And see what we can get from Mylar.
- You got it.
How long had Devin Frost
worked for you at the gym?
Couple years.
What was his relationship
with Chad Parkman?
Parkman had coached him
and brought him on as an assistant.
- Was Frost a member of Visualize?
- Him? I don't think so.
One thing about those Visualize nuts...
They got a work ethic.
And Frost not so much?
- Is that why you fired him?
- I didn't. He quit.
- Really? When?
- About a month ago.
Parkman went to a gymnastics
tournament in Europe.
In the past, Frost went with him.
This time, he didn't.
Instead he walked in, told me
he was quitting, walked out.
- Last time I saw him.
- He and Parkman get into a fight?
No, uh... I just figured he got
a better offer somewhere else
and was taking advantage of Parkman
not being around to quit to me.
Why would he do that?
Like I said, Parkman had been
Frost's mentor since he was a teenager.
I don't think he had the courage
to quit to Parkman's face.
- You think Mylar is our killer?
- Eh.
Me, neither.
Cooper was awfully cagey with you
about stiles' whereabouts, wasn't he?
After I spoke to Cooper,
I did some digging. Stiles is missing.
- Nobody knows where he is.
- Really? When?
Around the same time Red John sent you
The Lorelei Martins tape.
Boss? I just got Frost's phone records.
Look at this.
That's Ray Haffner's cell phone.
Frost called it three times
the week before he stabbed Parkman.
Well, let's go see what brother Ray
has to say about that.
He's not here. He went to the hotel.
He said he had to check on something.
- Then we'll go there.
- No, you stay here. Grace and I will go.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- We'll be fine.
He's more likely to let something slip to us
than he would to you.
All right. But what am I supposed to do
just sit around?
Well, we still haven't figured out
how Frost got out of the hotel room
after he stabbed Parkman.
Except Frost couldn't have been there
in the first place, could he?
You said it was a trick.
Figure it out.
I got the name of the sac P.D. detective
who investigated Kirkland's shooting.
- He's gonna come by CBI.
- Good work.
Hey, man. Usual, please.
- You want anything?
- Yeah, coffee. Black.
It's a fruit stand, Cho.
They sell fruit.
Okay. No.
Give me another one
with everything... lime, chili.
That's great.
Keep the change.
I'm starving.
I guess you burn a lot of calories
being a newlywed.
- We're not having this conversation.
- It's amazing.
You'd think that marriage
would just cool things off
but for us,
it's just the opposite.
Please stop talking.
You know, I think I'm
the happiest I've ever been.
Every morning when I wake up
next to her
and every night when we go
to bed together
I just think, "wow, I'm the luckiest
man in the world", you know?
- I just lost my appetite.
- So I wanna say thank you.
'cause you were the one
that made me take the risk.
- And I'm starting to regret it.
- No. You're a good friend, and I owe you.
I'm gonna find you
somebody to love.
- No. You're not.
- Yes, I am.
Trust me, there is no point
in going through life alone.
Are you really
not gonna eat that?
Thanks.
Hello. Teresa. Agent Van Pelt.
What brings you two here?
Why didn't you tell us you called Frost
the week before he Killed Parkman?
Look, there's nothing
suspicious about it.
I was hired by Visualize
to protect Parkman from Frost.
Bang-up job.
Frost was threatening
a wrongful termination suit.
I figured he was just
looking for a payout.
- What'd you say to him?
- Well, I told him that Visualize's lawyers
were behind Parkman,
and they'd keep it in the courts
until Frost had spent
his last penny.
What's wrong, Ray? These questions
making you uncomfortable?
Do you see that?
It's that.
It's a spider.
I hate spiders.
Better now?
Look. It...
It never occurred to me that Frost was
planning anything like a murder.
He didn't really strike me
as the violent type.
Live and learn, I guess.
Sometimes you get it wrong.
Next time you do better.
I've been trying to figure out
how Frost got away.
You know, the trick that
Jane can't figure out.
- And?
- Well, we know there was a third man.
- Yeah, the one who killed Frost.
- There had to be a fourth as well.
- An inside man.
- An inside man?
Or woman.
A maid, a cook, a bellboy, whatever.
Somebody who could help Frost get in
and out of the hotel without being seen.
There's no evidence Frost had contact
with any of the hotel's employees.
- We did interviews.
- So? Somebody lied to you.
The killer could have already been gone
by the time hotel security got to the room.
All the witnesses said they heard a struggle
going on inside the room.
Uh, there is a difference
between hearing and seeing.
Autopsy report just came out.
Parkman wasn't immediately
Killed from the knife wound.
He died from a struggle
sometime after being stabbed.
He had an aortal hemorrhage.
So... You're welcome.
How did you get
the autopsy before us?
I still have friends
in CBI, Teresa.
They help when I need it.
Speaking of...
helping friends
a word of advice
for both of you.
- Yeah? What's that?
- Jane.
He's made a mess of things.
He doesn't know when to leave
well enough alone.
- You know what I mean?
- No, I don't.
There's a lot of powerful people
that Jane's pissed off not just Red John.
You should get out of the way, both of you
before something happens.
- I really... I'd hate to see you get hurt.
- It's funny you should say that, Ray
because, actually, we're putting your name
on a list of suspects for Parkman's murder.
What? That's crazy.
The third man could have killed
both Frost and Parkman.
Frost killed Parkman.
Maybe the third man just
wanted it to look that way.
Maybe it's you, Ray. Maybe you're
the third man. You have motive.
I just hope you remember this.
That I tried to help. Okay?
I want to see that autopsy report.
Thanks for coming in, detective Cordero.
I really appreciate it.
Yeah. Call me Oscar.
Wow. Nice digs you got here.
No expense spared for you
CBI folks, huh?
Yeah. Can I get you something?
Coffee?
Nah, I'm fine.
Here's the file
on the Kirkland shooting.
It's got the prison report
plus my investigation.
- Anything that stuck out?
- Nah.
Only a sick puppy who couldn't
hack doing his time
looking for any way out...
in my opinion.
And you spoke to the correctional officer
who shot him?
Oh, yeah.
He was just a kid.
Says your guy Kirkland paid no attention
to three verbal warnings, just kept going
didn't even turn around.
Kid had to shoot.
You hate to see something
like that, you know?
Some piece of crap making a cop do
what he ain't got the stones to do himself.
It ain't right.
And I'll tell you somethin'.
Messed the kid up really bad.
P.T.S.D... Or something.
It's a damn shame.
- Can I make a copy of this?
- Don't need to.
Brought that one for you.
Thought you might want it.
- Thanks.
- Hey, no problem.
Maybe one day you'll do
a favor for me, right?
- He clear things up?
- Not really. I mean, he says it was clean.
Kirkland was trying to escape,
nobody wanted to shoot him
- but they were forced to... reluctantly.
- You don't buy it.
Well, it says in here
he was shot six times in the back.
- Six doesn't sound so reluctant.
- No, it doesn't.
- That's the story we're gonna get.
- Okay. I'll tell the boss.
Hi. Where can I find Kimball Cho?
That's his desk, but he
stepped out for a moment.
- Can I help you?
- Maybe. I met him this morning at the gym.
I thought I'd come by and see if he wants
to let me buy him a cup of coffee.
Plan seemed normal
when I was driving over here
but now it's feeling
a little stalker-ish.
- Does it seem stalker-ish to you?
- Mm, a little. Yeah.
- Okay, I should go.
- Hey.
- Remember me? Yeah.
- From the gym, yeah.
- Come here. Sit down for a second.
- Darn ankle.
Thanks.
What are you doing here?
My name's Kira.
Kira Tinsley.
I was gonna buy you a coffee
but it was a bad idea. I'm gonna go.
No, I can drink a cup of coffee.
Give me a second.
When Parkman was stabbed
the knife glanced over the rib
and barely nicked the aorta.
Haffner wasn't lying.
There coroner says that...
there was a struggle after the stabbing
that caused the nick to tear
and that's what started the hemorrhaging
that Killed Parkman.
And if Frost and Parkman
were really struggling
and that's what caused
the hemorrhage
how is it that Frost didn't get
Parkman's blood all over him?
And how did he avoid tracking
bloody footprints out of the room?
- Jane?
- I just solved the case.
- Really? How?
- Yeah. But one thing first.
Jane?
Grace? Who was that woman
Cho just met with?
Someone named Kira Tinsley.
- Oh, the woman he met at the gym?
- That's right.
- Attractive, right?
- She was okay, if you like that type.
- You... you ever go to the gym, Grace?
- Sure.
- You ever try to pick up a guy there?
- No.
Did they happen to say
where they were going?
Coffee.
Now you just walk out
in the middle of a conversation?
- Lisbon, can I ask a favor?
- What?
Can you go get one of those
elastic exercise bands
- the kind to help you stretch with?
- What do you need one of those for?
Bring it to Parkman's hotel room.
I'll meet you there.
What do I do?
Oh... Client relations. Boring stuff.
Tell me more about the CBI.
It's a job. Uh, we try to help people
Try to stop the bad guys.
- You don't talk much, do you?
- No.
It's all right.
- I like that in a man.
- Good.
- Hey, Cho.
- Hey.
- Kira Tinsley, right?
- Yeah.
Is that yours?
That looks good. May I?
What?
Nice muffin.
I think this is yours.
What is that?
I've never seen one of those.
It's a bug, a listening device.
Really? Because I found that
under Kimball's desk
and I was certain
that it belonged to you.
- Why would you say that?
- Because it goes with, uh...
this. Here.
And here's your wallet
and that identifies you
as a private investigator, doesn't it?
Yeah. All right. Okay.
That's why I don't take jobs like this,
but... the client paid cash up front, so...
- I'll take this. What?
- No, you can't... you can't have those.
You can't...
- Oops.
- That cost me 300 bucks.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Excuse me a minute.
Hey! Wait a minute.
Look, it was just business.
Nothing personal, okay?
- Your client...who was it?
- You know I can't reveal that.
All right, I'm arresting you under
section 632. That's worth a year in jail.
Hey, wait a second!
No, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We can work something out
here, right?
Jeez. What do you want to know?
What were you hired to do?
Bug your office, get close to you.
Client wanted to know everything
you and your team knew.
And who was your client?
Was it Visualize?
Yeah. So are we good?
- Are you Visualize?
- No.
I just work for whoever hires me.
- Are we done?
- Yeah, we're done.
Look, you seem like a nice guy.
Uh... no hard feelings?
Looks like she was hired by Visualize.
I'm gonna put a tail on her.
No need.
I put the bug in her bag.
We can listen to her whenever we like.
Let's go solve that
double murder, shall we?
Right.
Teresa. Any idea why we're here?
Your Mr. Jane asked us to come.
Are you gonna teach us aerobics?
Jane will be here any minute.
So the gun was found
somewhere here, right?
And the hotel is...
- That way, yes?
- Right.
You can't see it
but it's just the other side of that wall.
- I'm right.
- About what?
You stay here with Rigsby,
and keep very alert.
I don't want anyone
getting hurt.
Finally. We've been
waiting here long enough.
All good things come
to those who wait.
Thank you.
You gonna solve the case now
with a stretchy band?
Yes, among other things.
The first thing that's
important to note
is that Parkman and Frost
were lovers.
- Gay? No, they weren't.
- Yes, they were.
We never heard anything about that.
No. Because the relationship started
when Parkman was Frost's coach.
When Frost was still a minor.
And I never felt I had to worry
about him being alone with her.
Like I said, Parkman was Frost's mentor
since he was a teenager.
And continued to the present day?
Yes. Then the relationship
started going badly.
When Parkman went to Europe,
that was the final straw.
Mylar thought Frost was sneaking away
when Parkman wasn't looking.
Parkman went to a gymnastics
tournament in Europe.
In the past, Frost went with him.
This time, he didn't.
He had it backwards.
Parkman hadn't invited Frost.
So he assumed that he was being replaced
with a younger lover...
and decided to seek revenge.
So he tried filing
a wrongful termination suit
but he found himself being
intimidated by Visualize.
So he tried the hard touch
when Parkman came to the hotel
for the conference.
"Now their relationship had
always been a consensual one"
"but that wouldn't matter
in the eyes of the public or the law."
"It was in Frost's power
to transform Parkman"
"from a... an Olympic coach to a child
molester with just a few words."
"He demanded that Parkman
bring a large sum of money"
"across the park
in a brown paper bag."
"Or Frost would ruin
Parkman's life forever."
"And Frost was right in his estimation
of what Parkman stood to lose."
What he didn't realize was
how Parkman would react.
"The soda bottle
silencer worked perfectly."
"Even if it did blow off,
no one heard a thing."
"But Parkman hadn't expected
that Frost would have a knife."
"The wound looked to be minor"
"so Parkman put his gun back in his bag
and he left Frost."
"Already Parkman was
starting to panic."
"What happened in the car
hadn't gone to plan."
"Nothing was going to plan."
Whoa! What the heck!
And when you arrived
Parkman was trying to figure out
what to do with the gun.
The window was his only chance.
He couldn't just throw it out there, though.
It would end up right down there
in the street.
But... If he could just
- "Mr. Parkman?"
- Get it...
a little... Further.
Just that little... bit...
Further.
What the hell?
"When the gun landed on the ground
in the alley, it went off."
"That was the gunshot
that witnesses heard."
TV remote.
Very likely we'll find a bullet hole
somewhere in the alley.
But who Killed Parkman?
Where'd all the blood come from?
When Parkman
pulled on the elastic...
his aorta ruptured.
Fore!
What the hell?
Help.
He stabbed me.
So you're telling me that nobody
came in or out of the room.
It was just Mr. Parkman
the whole time?
Yeah.
The trick was
that there was no trick.
Et voilà.
Good-bye, agent Lisbon,
Mr. Jane.
I hope you won't be insulted when I say
that I hope I won't be seeing you again.
Oh, we won't be.
I'm sure Mr. Haffner would say
thank you if he were here.
Where is he? It's not like him to leave
without one last barbed compliment.
Oh, he had some business
to attend to.
I am not his only client.
I was hoping your office
could be discreet.
- You know what I mean.
- Yes.
Speaking... of discreet
it was stupid of you
to try and bug the CBI.
What are you talking about?
Hiring someone outside Visualize
might have made you feel safe
but she admitted
that you hired her.
Agent Cho told me.
I don't know what you're talking about.
But all I can say is that if someone
did bug you it wasn't me.
Bye, agent Lisbon.
Jane? Are you okay?
- Grace needs to trace this immediately.
- Why? What's going on?
Cooper wasn't lying.
He didn't bug the CBI.
- Well, who did?
- Red John. We need to find Kira Tinsley.
She either works for Red John, or she's
about to become his next victim.
"She's in the north section
of the city, boss."
"Van Pelt's working
on the address."
No answer on her cell,
and the landline's busy.
- Yeah, we know.
- "Yeah, you say 9:00 to 6:00"
"and then you never even show up."
Almost got it.
No. I paid my cleaning lady
to stay here all day
to let the guy in,
and then he never came.
Okay.
1065 Oak Terrace.
We're on Douglas,
headed toward Folsom.
Yeah. No, I want my cable
fixed now, tonight or I'm gonna...
I'm g... yeah, hold on a second.
Somebody's here.
I need SAC P.D. to 1065 Oak Terrace
as fast as they can.
Okay, I'm coming!
Oh, hi.
Okay, you're about ten minutes away.
We'll direct you.
Could you drive faster?
- "Help."
- Oh, crap.
Boss, you're gonna want to
take the next left...
and then a right on El Camino.
Got a patrol car
six blocks away.
Police! I'm coming in.
SAC P.D.'s on scene.
Come on. Oh, come on,
stay with me.
Stay with me. You're gonna be okay.
Come on, stay with me.
Right on El Camino, boss.
- Damn it.
- Just drive, Lisbon.
"I need E.M.T.S.
I need medical assistance immediately."
Now look at me.
You're gonna be fine, okay?
They're on their way.
Wait...
Where are the E.M.T.S?
We need E.M.T.S.
I'm CBI. Who did this to you?
Tell me.
Tattoo...
Tattoo on his left arm.
What did she say?
She told me Red John has a tattoo
on his left shoulder.
Three dots.
That's my leverage. I got him.